M: +966 54 2904596

E: jurjengroen@gmail.com

W: https://sa.linkedin.com/in/jurjengroen

JURJEN GROEN

PROFILE

Project Management Professional with 16 years of experience in vertical, infrastructure and utilities development for Cities, Ports, Special Economic Zones and Free Zones. Successfully managed projects from master planning to engineering and construction in Europe (Port of Rotterdam) and the Middle East (Sohar Port & Freezone, Khalifa Port, Kizad, King Abdullah Economic City and Industrial Valley). Self-motivated and energetic individual, driven by project success and delivery within the overall business strategy. Strong interpersonal skills, ensuring the development of good working relationships with all parties involved. A 'deep' generalist with a broader perspective, excellent collaborative approach to work, ensuring integration of the project's and customer's needs. Currently working on the development of the 65km² greenfield Industrial Valley as part of the extraordinary 180km² King Abdullah Economic City (KAEC) in Saudi Arabia, the world's largest privately funded real estate project, including port (King Abdullah Port), residential, commercial and industrial developments.

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

Project Management Permitting Process
Stakeholder Management Project Controls
Project Cost Feasibility Ports
Utilities Planning Change Management
Engineering Management Tenant Lease Agreements
Real Estate Development Construction Management

Rules & Regulations
Land Use Planning
One Stop Shop
Economic Zones
Contract Management
Training & Mentoring

EXPERIENCE

SR. DEVELOPMENT MANAGER - INDUSTRIAL VALLEY

Emaar, the Economic City (KSA)

May 2014 - Present

Emaar, the Economic City is a JV between Emaar Properties and a number of high profile investors from Saudi Arabia and the main developer of the US\$ 95bn King Abdullah Economic City project. As Sr. Development Manager, I am responsible for the delivery of the master planning and vertical development programme of the 65km² greenfield Industrial Valley through the following key projects/ activities:

- Detailed Master Plans of 16.5km² Industrial Valley incl. the Port connected Bonded & Re-export Zone, covering logistics, industrial, mixed-use and worker housing land uses (US\$ 5m).
- Design-Bid-Build of 55,000m² (Phase 1 & 2) Pre-Built Warehouses (US\$ 35m).
- Design-Bid-Build of 5,000m² (Phase 1) Commercial Offices (US\$ 10m).
- Design-Bid-Build of 6,000m² Commercial Office refurbishment (US\$ 5m).
- Technical coordination for several feasibility studies, including Islamic Free Trade Zone, Cold Storage Facility, Multi-Modal Logistics Terminal and Natural Gas distribution network.

I am reporting to the Executive Director of Construction and Project Management.

SR. PROJECT MANAGER - INDUSTRIAL ZONE DEVELOPMENT

Abu Dhabi Ports Company (UAE)

Sep 2007 – Apr 2014

Abu Dhabi Ports Company is the main developer of all ports and related industrial zones in Abu Dhabi, including the US\$ 7bn Khalifa Port & Industrial Zone Project. As Sr. Project Manager, I was responsible for the delivery of the US\$1bn main infrastructure development programme of the

51km² greenfield Khalifa Industrial Zone Abu Dhabi (Kizad) through the following key projects/activities, leading to its successful completion on 01.09.12 and Royal opening on 12.12.12:

- Conceptual Master Plan 'Kizad 2030' 418km² (US\$1.5m).
- Design-Bid-Build of 66km of multi-lane roads, bridges & utility networks (US\$688m).
- Execution of 40 million m³ mass earthworks for 27km² Kizad land (US\$272m).
- Design-Build of 11,000m³/day Sewage Treatment Plant (US\$21m).
- Design-Build of 5nos. 33/11kV Electrical Substations (US\$90m).
- Design-Build of 44,000m² of Pre-Built Warehouses (US\$28m).
- Design-Build of 15km of 16bar Gas Distribution Network (US\$45m).
- Design-Build of 5,000m³/day Reverse Osmosis (RO) plant (US\$7m).

I was reporting to the Vice President – Major Projects.

Project awards: GCC Infrastructure Project of The Year Award 2010, Outstanding Development of the Year Award 2011, Abu Dhabi Award for Excellence in Government Performance 2013.

PROJECT MANAGER – INFRASTRUCTURE & UTILITIES

Sohar Industrial Port Company (Sultanate of Oman)

Jan 2005 - Sep 2007

Sohar Industrial Port Company is a 50/50 JV between the Port of Rotterdam and the Omani Government and the main developer of the 20km² Sohar Industrial Port & Free Zone. As Project Manager, I was responsible for the main road & utilities infrastructure development through the following main activities:

- Coordination with the Ministry of Transport to ensure incorporation of the Port Authority's functional and technical requirements in the design of the landside infrastructure (US\$141m).
- Analysis and development of utility strategies (water, power, gas and telecom) in coordination with the Government entities and utility companies in order to support the Port Tenants.
- Technical support to Business Development to enable effective Tenant plot allocation.
- Setup of the organization's Technical Department and training of Omani technical staff.

I was reporting to the Executive Technical Manager.

PROJECT MANAGER - CONTRACTS & SITE LEASE

Port of Rotterdam (The Netherlands)

Apr 2003 - Dec 2004

The Port of Rotterdam Authority is the developer, operator and manager of the 105km² Rotterdam Port and Industrial area, which is the largest port in Europe. As Project Manager, I was responsible for the tenant plot allocation process and the preparation and negotiation of lease agreements with various industrial and logistics tenants in the Rotterdam Port. I also developed (in-house) the Conceptual Masterplan for 'Maasvlakte North-West 2020'. I was reporting to the Manager of Projects.

ASSISTANT PROJECT MANAGER - PORT DEVELOPMENT

Port of Rotterdam (The Netherlands)

Sep 2001 – Apr 2003

As Assistant Project Manager, I supported the Project Manager in the delivery of maritime infrastructure projects in the existing 'Maasvlakte' area of the Rotterdam Port:

- Design-Bid-Build of 2,000m deep sea quay wall for Euromax Terminal (US\$ 190m).
- Design-Bid-Build of 500m deep sea quay wall for DFDS Tor Line (US\$ 50m).

I was reporting to the Project Manager.

RESEARCHER PPP

P3BI (The Netherlands)

Mar 2001 - Apr 2001

P3BI is a research centre for the implementation of integrated construction processes, with the focus on the application of PPP, Design and Construct and other Integrated Contracts. As Researcher, I supported the Assistant Professor in her research on Public Private Partnership (PPP) developments in The Netherlands. I reviewed and assessed potential PPP projects and developed a database for effective recording of the findings. I was reporting to the Assistant Professor.

ASSISTANT BID MANAGER

Strukton Integrale Projecten (The Netherlands)

Mar 2000 - Feb 2001

Strukton Integrale Projecten is a subsidiary of Strukton NV and specializes in managing and investing in PPP projects in The Netherlands and Europe. As Assistant Bid Manager, I provided technical support in the preparation of tenders for PPP projects. I developed a management tool for assessing the feasibility of PPP projects and reviewed the feasibility of projects in the pre-tender stage. I was reporting to the Bid Manager.

SITE ENGINEER

Wedge Projects (South Africa)

Apr 1999 - Sep 1999

Wedge Projects is a consulting firm, specialised in the engineering and project management of infrastructure projects. As Site Engineer, I assisted the Project Site Manager in the administrative, contractual and financial aspects of a 25km sewage pipeline project in Pretoria as part of the Heatherdale and Klerksoord city development. I was reporting to the Project Site Manager.

EDUCATION

INSEAD (FONTAINEBLEAU, FRANCE)

Port of Rotterdam Young Executives Programme

Apr 2004

Key areas: Leadership foundation & skills, Strategic insight, Business knowledge & tools.

UNIVERSITY OF TWENTE (ENSCHEDE, THE NETHERLANDS)

MSc. Civil Engineering & Management

Sep 1994 - Feb 2001

Major: Construction & Construction Processes.

Thesis: "Feasibility Indicators of Project Financed Integrated projects".

THIJ COLLEGE (OLDENZAAL, THE NETHERLANDS)

Secondary Education

Sep 1988 – Jun 1994

LANGUAGES

Dutch (mother tongue), English (fluent), German (very good)

INTERESTS

Travel, 4x4 off-road, running, sailing, skiing, kite-surf, wake board, scuba diving, photo, video

Sex: Male

PERSONAL INFORMATION

Date of Birth: 02 August 1976

Driver's License: Yes (KSA & NL)

Nationality: Dutch

Marital Status: Married

Children: Three